Pham Huy Hoang

Developer Phone: 07922.819.535 (UK) Email: huyhoang8a5@gmail.com



SUMMARY

I'm a web developer with 2 years of experience in C#.NET technologies, with good knowledge of Object-Oriented Analysis and Design, Database Design, Design Pattern.

Learning new languages and technologies (I self-taught Django with 3 weeks) is what I am passionate about. I am considered a team-player because I like to help other and tend to work well within group. I can also do some mentoring tasks and do code reviewing for other team members.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages:
 - C# .NET/ Java/ Python
 - HTML5 / CSS3 / Javascript
- Frameworks/ Platforms:
 - ASP.NET MVC 4 / WebForm / WinForm / WPF
 - ASP WebAPI / RESTfulAPI
 - Entity Framework / LINQ to SQL
 - ¡Query /Twister Bootstrap
- Database Management Systems:
 - MS SQL Server/ MySQL
 - MongoDB
- Others:

- Version Control:
 - SVN (TortoiseSVN & VisualSVN)
 - Team Foundation Server
 - Git (Git Shell & Github)
- Foreign Languages:

English:

- TOEIC 940/990
- IELTS: 7.5
- Soft Skills:
 - Time management
 - Business communication
 - Teamwork
- Understand about: OOP methodology, design patterns, Agile and Scrum
 - Immediate Photoshop skill. Can do simple design: logo, banner, poster....

EDUCATION

FPT University Ho Chi Minh

From 11/2010 to 01/2014

- Top 5 graduated student in 2014. GPA: 88%. Degree rank: Good (Equivalent to 1st in UK).
- Chosen as the Team Leader in the Capstone Project. Highest Capstone Project score in that semester.

Nguyen Du High School (Buon Ma Thuot City)

• GPA: 88%. Degree rank: Good.

From 2007 to 2010

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASWIG Solutions 09/2014 - Now

Position: Developer Project: Foundation

• **Project Description**: A system which serves as a gateway, checks the authentication and authorization of the users from other applications.

Team Size: 5Responsibilities:

Meeting with customers and teammates to get clear requirement.

Develop the frameworks and modules of the system.

• Accomplishments:

Learned new Microsoft technologies and frameworks.

Improved teamwork and communication skills.

• **Technologies:** ASP.NET MVC5. AngularJS. Claim-based Identity. Thinktecture Identity Server.

FPT Software Ho Chi Minh

01/2014 - 08/2014

Position: Junior Developer Project: Nebula - Simulator

• **Project Description**: A system simulates the process of constructing an oil well. The purpose of the system is to help training junior petroleum engineers.

Team Size: 12Responsibilities:

Communicate with customer to get clear requirement.

Develop and fix the application's defect base on requirement.

Prepare document and technical guide for developers joining in the middle of the project.

Accomplishments:

Learned to develop software follow Scrum development process.

Learned WPF, Caliburn, Micro Model-View-View Model framework.

Got experience in working/communicate with America customers.

Technologies: XAML & WPF. Caliburn Micro.

PASTTIMES AND ACTIVITIES

- I am keen of reading books in my free time. My favorite book is "How to win friends and influence people" by Dale Carnegie. I am enthusiastic in doing extra curriculum and voluntary activities, such as charity events.
- My other hobby is blogging, as I am the author of a Vietnamese IT blog called toidicodedao.com, where I share my working experience and knowledge to other developers. My profile ranks among top 10% programmers on <u>stackoverflow.com</u> – an international Q&A site for programmers.